Do you have a friend who happily agrees to your plans, only to disappear when the time eventually comes?
你有没有这样的朋友，当初欣然同意你的计划，结果到了时间却消失了？
Maybe they flake on you and cancel last minute, or just don't tell you and then ghost you completely.
也许他们放你鸽子，最后一刻取消，或者干脆不告诉你，然后完全消失。
Or just maybe, it's you that sometimes lets people down.
又或者，也许让别人失望正是你自己。
What lies behind this reluctance to keep to engagements?
这种不愿信守约定的背后是什么？
It could be our personality traits.
可能是我们的性格。
According to psychology professor Richard Koestner, less conscientious or agreeable people tend to have less concern for others and are more likely to overbook themselves socially.
根据心理学教授理查德·克斯特纳的说法，责任感或随和性较低的人往往对他人的关心较少，更容易让自己的社交活动安排过满。
While this can be due to bad time management, it can also be because people are afraid of confrontation and saying no to their friends, so end up agreeing to things that they don't really want to do.
虽然这可能是因为时间管理不善，但也可能是因为人们害怕与朋友产生冲突或直接拒绝，结果就答应了自己并不想做的事情。
Technology could be another factor behind people's willingness to back out of social commitments.
技术可能是人们愿意退出社交承诺的另一个因素。
Firstly, being able to cancel plans with a simple text message or pressing a 'not attending' button on an invitation, rather than doing it face-to-face or through an awkward phone call, is a much more frictionless way to say you have changed your mind.
首先，通过一条简单的短信或点击邀请上的"不参加"按钮来取消计划，而不是面对面或通过尴尬的电话来取消，是一种更顺畅的方式来表达你改变了主意。
On top of this, people have become used to the instant gratification offered by social media and streaming platforms.
除此之外，人们已经习惯了社交媒体和流媒体平台带来的即时满足感。
Does this make real-life interaction seem mundane and arduous by comparison?
这是否让现实生活中的互动相比之下显得单调而费力？
Could it be generational?
这会是代际差异吗？
A 2017 study found that 45% of American millennials saw nothing wrong with withdrawing from social arrangements.
2017年的一项研究发现，45%的美国千禧一代认为退出社交安排并没有什么不妥。
Older generations were less likely to pull out of events that they had been invited to.
老一辈人则不太可能退出他们被邀请的活动。
Whatever lies behind it, psychologists have advice for us.
无论背后是什么原因，心理学家都给我们提出了建议。
Kurt Gray from the University of North Carolina recommends a simple phone call to reinforce human connection.
北卡罗来纳大学的库尔特·格雷建议打一个简单的电话来加强人际关系。
Andrea Bonior from Georgetown University tells us to gently let our friends know that being let down disrupts us and makes us feel less valued.
乔治城大学的安德里亚·博尼奥尔告诉我们，要温和地让朋友知道，被放鸽子会扰乱我们，让我们觉得自己不受重视。
Caution is important though.
不过，谨慎也很重要。
Life coach Kira Asatryan reminds us that sometime people withdraw, not out of disrespect, but because they themselves feel anxious, stressed or sad.
生活教练基拉·阿萨特里安提醒我们，有时人们退出，不是因为不尊重，而是因为他们自己感到焦虑、压力大或悲伤。